Anna Ivahnenko

Driven professional with a strong analytical background. Looking to leverage my data storytelling and problem-solving skills to build upon my 5+ years of experience in data science by transitioning to research and journalism

073 9382 1784 anna.ivahk@gmail.com London, SE Linkedin

EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist — Assembly, Stagwell London | Oct 2020 - Sep 2023

Worked with a global client base, addressing diverse data challenges:

- Conducted Causal Impact & AB testing using R and Python analysis
- Optimised results in **diminishing returns analysis** by implementing **dynamic time-warping in Python**
- Applied custom R ensemble method package for demand forecasting
- Collaborated on Marketing Mixed Models using the Python Robyn library providing Adstock and channel importance
- Automated client-specific **Big Query** reporting and **website flow analysis**
- Led data cleaning and feature engineering for forecasting and MMM projects using SQL and R

Research Scientist — GTB, WPP

London | Mar 2019 - Sep 2019

As a part of the Marketing Analytics team, analysed the Ford EU website clickstream, sales, and media budget data:

- Applied advanced neural networks for user behaviour analysis, forecast of key sites and visitor segmentation, media campaigns analysis, and optimization of customer journey funnel for multiple markets
- Established an ETL process for merging, transforming and processing big data to score as well as compare **omni-channel** campaigns
- Collaborated with multiple marketing teams to set KPIs against client feedback interpreting client specifications and providing feedback
- **Trained** new data analysts on tools, technologies, and presentations

Data Analyst — GTB, WPP

London | Sep 2016 - Sep 2018

Worked on Ford's media budget, website clickstream data and reported sales analysis. I used SQL, Python, Adobe Analytics, Tableau, and Excel to:

- Implemented advanced machine learning methods for long-term forecasting of key site actions
- Working in a team to build an **attribution model** that links media channels, markets and visitor actions to improve performance
- Provide insight into visitor journeys, producing insights for campaigns and site optimisation
- Produced and presented **deep dive post-campaign analytics**, quarterly and weekly **business reviews**, aiding clients in future **campaign planning**

Skills

Time Series Forecasting
Segmentation & Clusterisation
Optimization & Attribution
Data Analysis
Data Visualisation
Reporting

Languages

Python, R, SQL, SAS, HTML, CSS, JS

Machine Learning

Pandas, Sklearn, SciPy, MLflow, SPSS, Dplyr, GGplot2, Keras, Robyn, NLP

Tools

Git (CI/CD), Visual Studio, D3, Tableau, Google Looker Studio, Power BI, Excel, Databricks, GCP

Certificates

LinkedIn Learning:

Advanced Python Programming
R Statistics Training
D3.js Training for DS
Advanced SQL for Data Science
Applied ML Feature Engineering
UX Accessibility Foundations
Interactive Tableau Dashboards
Git Training
Hidden Value of Open Data

 $MIT\ Open Course Ware:$

Linear Algebra by Gilbert Strang

EDUCATION

M.Sc. Data Science — University of Edinburgh

2019 - 2020 | Graduated with Merit

Modules: Machine Learning and Pattern Recognition, Cloud Computing, Data Mining and Exploration, Text Technologies, Reinforcement Learning, Data Visualisation, SAS for Financial Analysis and Bioinformatics

B.Sc. Maths and Computer Science — University of Stirling

2012 - 2016 | Graduated in with 2:1 degree

PROJECTS

Twitter Sentiment Analysis Project — *Team Project* | 2020

- Leveraged the **Twitter API** to gather keyword-specific data for a climate change **sentiment analysis** and **visualisation** assignment
- Conducted a comprehensive one-week preliminary data analysis
- Visualised and communicated findings using D3, Tableau, and Plotly

Hospital Capacity Forecasting — Dissertation | 2020

- Optimised Royal Infirmary of Edinburgh ward transitions through advanced ML forecasting
- Developed a high-accuracy prediction visualisation tool (97%) for proactive hospital planning
- Conducted a thorough comparison of advanced deep learning forecasting methods for reproducibility

Recipe Finder Website — Team Project | 2020

- **Led a dynamic team** of six in the creation of a website recommending recipes based on available ingredients
- Integrated diverse skills, including web scraping, text processing, machine learning, and web development

Spread of Infectious Diseases — Dissertation | 2016

- Modelled dynamics of 'susceptible,' 'infected,' and 'recovered' individuals during infectious outbreaks
- Identified critical factors influencing disease propagation patterns
- Implemented the SIRS model in **Python**, documented using LaTeX, and delivered a compelling presentation to university associates

Research into Vaccine Scares — *Project* | 2016

- Conducted a thorough vaccine efficiency **modelling methods comparison**
- Determined vaccination requirements to effectively curb disease spread
- Completed the project within three weeks, presenting detailed results in a comprehensive report

Achievements

UK Mathematical Contest in Modelling at Stirling University Achieved a distinction in problem modelling and writing a paper, working in a team

Army Leadership in Practice Course Developing leadership, followership, planning, time management, effective communication and positive personal impact skills

University Army Officer Training Corps

I accomplished a MOD Alpha. During 9 months my leadership, teamwork, discipline, organisation, critical analysis, communication, and coordination skills were tested and improved.

Erasmus Study Abroad
Studied for six months in Italy,
learning to adapt to various new
assessment styles. Having to
take personal responsibilities,
communicate and build
relationships.

Interests

Hiking Open data projects Cycling Photography Climbing